Manuel Olguín Muñoz

https://olguin.se Mobile: +46-73-652-7628

SUMMARY

Doctoral student at the School of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science of KTH Royal Institute of Technology, with research interests broadly in the area of mobile and cloud computing, pervasive computing and low-latency systems and architectures. Doctoral advisor is James Gross, PhD.

Present Position

• KTH Royal Institute of Technology

PhD. Student, School of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science

Stockholm, Sweden

Started: September 2017

Email: manuel@olguin.se

EDUCATION

• KTH Royal Institute of Technology

PhD., Electrical Engineering

Stockholm, Sweden

Sep. 2017 — Sep. 2022 (expected)

• Universidad de Chile

Engineer's Degree, Computer Science; Final Grade: 6.5/7.0

Santiago, Chile Mar. 2011 — Aug. 2017

• Universidad de Chile

B.Eng.Sc., Computer Science; Final Grade: 5.4/7.0

Santiago, Chile

Mar. 2011 — Aug. 2017

Academic & Research Experience

• KTH Royal Institute of Technology

Teaching Assistant

Stockholm, Sweden

Mar. 2018 — May 2018

o EQ1120 Discrete Time Signals and Systems: Course on discrete-time signals and systems, how they can be described and analyzed by using difference equations and transform methods, and be implemented in software like Matlab. Duties included teaching and grading.

• NIC Chile Research Labs

Santiago, Chile

 $Research\ Assistant$

Jan. 2016 — June 2017

- PVEINS: Developed a plugin integrating a discrete event simulator (OMNeT++) with a traffic simulator (Paramics), in order to simulate large-scale Intelligent Transport System scenarios. This software was then presented as part of a Engineer's Degree Thesis.
- Early Warning System for Bikes in ITS: Worked on an early warning system for bicycles in an Intelligent Transport System, as part of a research project under the supervision of Sandra Céspedes, PhD.

Universidad de Chile

Santiago, Chile

Teaching Assistant

Aug. 2013 — Jun. 2017

- o CC1000 Computer Tools for Engineering and Science: Introductory course on computation tools, algorithmic thinking and basic computer science concepts for first year students. Duties including providing assistance at a weekly workshop and grading.
- o CC3001 Algorithms and Data Structures: Course on the fundamentals of algorithms (sorting, search), complexity, data structures, abstract data types and graphs. Duties included teaching and grading.
- CC1002 Introduction to Programming: Course on basic programming concepts, methodologies and strategies. Duties included teaching and grading.
- o CC3501 Computer Graphics, Visualization and Modeling for Engineers: Course on the fundamentals of graphical programming and modeling, as well as data visualization, and how these disciplines can be applied in an interdiciplinary manner. Duties included homework design, teaching and grading.

Other Experience

• Epistemonikos Foundation

Santiago, Chile

Software Developer

Aug. 2016 — Dec. 2016

• In-House Software: Designed and deployed a number of in-house software solutions to optimize workflow and improve efficiency in the activities of the foundation (principally in the form of RESTful web services).

Note: this activity was part of a mandatory advanced course on Software Development and Project Management.

Standford Honors Academy

Santiago, Chile

Teaching Assistant

Jan. 2016

• Game Design: Worked as a Teaching Assistant for the Game Design class at the Stanford Honors Academy, an initiative by Stanford University and Education, to bring American post-graduate students and teachers as tutors for advanced topics at a summer camp for promising middle- and high school students in their own home countries.

• NIC Chile Research Labs

Santiago, Chile

 $Software\ Developer$

Aug. 2015 — Dec. 2015

• Image-management Microservice: Designed, implemented and deployed a backend microservice for image management in client-server applications for Android devices. Internal NICLabs project.

Conferences & Workshops

• ACM HotMobile 2019

Santa Cruz, CA

Paper Presentation

Feb. 27-28 2019

• ACM/IEEE SEC 2018

Bellevue, WA

Poster Presentation

Oct. 25-27 2018

Languages

Spanish (Native), English (Fluent), Swedish (Fluent).

Extracurricular Activities, Interests & Misc.

Social Dance at KI

Stockholm, Sweden

Volunteer

Jan. 2017 — Current

• Cuban Salsa and Rueda de Casino Instructor: Social Dance at KI is one of the projects of the Medical Society at Karolinska Institutet, organized once every week, that offers dance lessons in Salsa LA, Salsa Cubana, Rueda and Bachata, on beginner and beginner/intermediate level.

• Beauchef Intl. Community

Santiago, Chile

Student Member

2014 - 2017

• Board Member: The Beauchef International Community is the international community of Universidad de Chile's Faculty of Physical and Mathematical Sciences, tasked with welcoming and guiding international students during their time in Chile.

• Pedalea! Beauchef

Santiago, Chile

Student Member

2013 - 2015

• Bike Mechanic and Board Member: Pedalea! Beauchef is a organization formed by students of the Faculty of Physical and Mathematical Sciences of Universidad de Chile, with the goal of fostering bicycle culture amongst students. The organization maintains a bicycle repair workshop on campus and organizes a multitude of events every semester.

• ATA Taekwondo

Santiago, Chile

1st Degree Black Belt

2008 - 2013

Publications	
[1]	Manuel Olguín Muñoz, Junjue Wang, Mahadev Satyanarayanan, and James Gross. 2019. EdgeDroid: An Experimental Approach to Benchmarking Human-in-the-Loop Applications. In <i>The 20th International Workshop on Mobile Computing Systems and Applications (HotMobile '19)</i> . Accepted paper submission.
[2]	Manuel Olguín Muñoz, Junjue Wang, Mahadev Satyanarayanan, and James Gross. 2018. Demo: Scaling on the Edge – A Benchmarking Suite for Human-in-the-Loop Applications. In 2018 IEEE/ACM Symposium on Edge Computing (SEC), 323–325. DOI: 10.1109/SEC.2018.00031.
[3]	Manuel Olguín Muñoz. 2017. Diseño e Implementación de un Framework Integrado para Simulaciones de Sistemas Inteligentes de Transporte en OMNeT++ y Paramics. Engineer's Degree Thesis. Universidad de Chile, Santiago, Chile. http://repositorio.uchile.cl/handle/2250/147392.